Danny Castonguay

Product leader

Email: danny@talented.app
Web: www.dannycastonguay.com

About Me

I'm the founder of Talented.app and the co-Founder of Kalibrr.com. I'm a former McKinsey Expert Associate Partner. I'm a husband and father of three. I train Brazilian Jui-Jitsu 5 times a week and I don't compromise on sleep, nutrition, and meditation/relaxation. I challenge my teams, I create accountability structure, and I give a lot of (tough) love.

Tools I like to use include: Gitlab, SKLearn, and Figma.

I am most skilled in: Business, Product Management, and Team Health.

Experience

Talented.app

talented.app

Founder & CEO

2018 - Present

Talented assembles high performance, low overhead teams in days.

I built a network of boutique software consulting agencies (design, data science, development, and video animations) with over 500 people between North America, Eastern Europe, Israel, India, and the Philippines. I launched product teams at 5+ clients. For instance, at a Big Five tech company, I am leading the team building a digital twin for the physical flow infrastructure to predict failures, and make real time deployment of the mobile fleet to keep data centers alive in case of disruptions.

McKinsey & Company

mckinsey.com

Expert Associate Partner

2007 - 2010, 2013 - 2017

McKinsey & Company is the trusted advisor and counselor to many of the world's most influential businesses and institutions.

I served companies in several industries, including railroads, mining, refining, oil & gas (upstream and downstream), electricity production and distribution, banking, retail, and non-profits. My lead role consisted in scoping, building and deploying software solutions (machine learning, mobile apps, data pipelines) and crafting executive communication. For example, a scheduling tool I built saved a logistics company several hundred millions of dollars annually in fuel, crews and equipment. I was also an internal faculty to teach machine learning to other consultants and I led an initiative to connect with academics on topics such as deep learning, reinforcement learning, quantum computing, game theory, and robust optimization.

Kalibrr

kalibrr.com

Co-Founder, CTO

2012 - 2013

Kalibrr helps people get hired at the best companies in Southeast Asia, with 2M+ users, 800+ companies, and 66,000+ hires in 2018. Raised \$5M, including Y-Combinator.

I built the engineering and design team and led product management for the talent marketplace. Went from 0 to 100K users in less than 12 months.

MIT | UP Diliman

https://gsl.mit.edu/

Instructor | Adjunct Professor

2012 - 2013

MIT GSL trains and funds top MIT students and alumni to conduct technology incubator courses globally.

I led 100+ undergrad/grad students through two semesters. I created the curiculum for an intensive course going from idea generation to rapid prototyping and user testing. I organized hackathons and investor presentations. Two teams presented at Google Developers Day Philippines.

Education

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

MBA

2011 - 2013

Awarded a \$50,000 fellowship by the Legatum Center for Development and Entrepreneurship.

During my time at MIT, I took classes such as Linked Data Ventures with Tim Berners-Lee, Sustainability with Jason Jay, Macro-econ with Roberto Rigobon, and Robust Optimization with Dimitris Bertsimas. I also co-founded Kalibrr and joined Y-Combinator during my last semester.

McGill University

Undergrad and Master of Electrical, Computer and Software Engineering

2001 - 2006

Awarded both provincial scholarship by the FQRNT, and federal scholarship by the NSERC.

As an Undergrad I took several graduate level courses such as Articifial Intelligence, Random Processes, Human Computer Interface, and Game Theory. I completed a Master's Thesis under Shie Mannor, the (then) Canadian Chair of Machine Learning.

A Little More About Me

Alongside my interests in technology, design, sustainability, education, and finance, some of my other interests and hobbies are:

- · Muay Thai, Jiu Jitsu, Yoga
- Meditation
- · Card, board, and video games

Danny Castonguay - danny@talented.app - References on request